MARC MOTEN

Garland, TX 75043

Phone: 972-971-3397 | Email: marcmotenii@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/marcmotenii | GitHub: https://github.com/Mamii868

Portfolio: https://mamii868.github.io/React-Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer prepared to learn and develop my skills through experience. I have recently received a certificate in full stack development from Southern Methodist University, acquiring skills in web design, CSS, Javascript, React.js, and MySQL. I have especially learned how to work as a team to build different programs in this course, giving me vital experience of working on projects. Coming from a background in music, I have been able to use my ability to adapt to what I am working on to quickly learn and accomplish tasks as well as work with different people. As I explore the world of coding I aim to constantly hone my skills as well as gear apps I work on to provide the best user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Applications: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, MySQL, React

PROJECTS

DeFi101 | Github: https://github.com/Mamii868/Defi-101

Website: https://mamii868.github.io/Defi-101

- This application lets you search different cryptocurrencies, gives an introduction to cryptocurrency, and shows news regarding the specific currency selected
- I created a separate page showing videos to teach about crypto as well as a news portion that updates based on what currency is selected.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Collection Social Share | Github: https://github.com/Mamii868/collection_social_share Website: https://collection_social_share

- This application is a take on social media for collectors, allowing you to upload pictures of your collections online to show off.
- I was tasked with using MySQL to create a database to store and pull the accounts and collections as well as design the pages.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, NodeJS, Express

App Track | Github: https://github.com/Mamii868/app-track Website: https://powerful-reaches-64620.herokuapp.com

- This application lets users create an account and manage job applications on a job board. The user is prompted with places to fill in information as well as an option to scrape data from LinkedIn about the job posting.
- I created and managed the database and most functions interacting with the information using GraphQL.
- Tools / languages used: HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, React, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express

EXPERIENCE

Secretary2020 - PresentLindstrom Law FirmMesquite, TX

- Provided a faster way of managing clients by using a database to keep track of information.
- Assisted in gathering a large list of potential clients and business partners to grow the company's network.
- Managed new office location to ensure cleanliness and optimal communication with the main office.

Senior Lifeguard 2019 - 2021 Garland Aquatics Garland, TX

- Properly sanitized and maintained park to maintain cleanliness and quality standards of Garland Aquatics.
- Used critical judgment skills to uphold the standard of safety inside the facility Key Accomplishments:
 - Informally recognized as one of the driving forces of the workforce at the facility.
 - Constant recognition from the higher-ups for outstanding effort and results.

EDUCATION

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX

April 2021 - October 2021

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

Dallas College, Dallas, TX

2020-2021

Completed one full year